well it's the earning season and we have
ICICI Lombard management talking to us
about a great set of numbers that came
out yesterday um we have Mr gopal
balachandran the Chief Financial Officer
at ICI Lombard welcome to the show
sir good morning everyone and thanks to
thanks for having me uh as a part of uh
the show
today IC Lombard reported a net profit
of uh around 432 CR which was up 22%
while it was a slight Miss on the
Bloomberg estimates overall positive
numbers the motor segment reported an
over double digit growth uh I mean they
came up they doubled their operating
profits net premium income was up 133%
solvency ratio came in pretty strong
combined ratio also seems to be on track
at
103.6 I think which is inclusive of some
uh catastrophic event losses that we saw
the quar um sir thank you so much for
joining us today uh we have a couple of
questions here motor has been one of
your focus areas for um the past year
and we've been talking very closely
about it um we finally seeing a lot of
good results there what has worked and
how are the loss shows also coming out
on this front U are we in a comparable
position what is happening sir yeah I
think that's a great question to start
off with uh I think let me put this in
the context of the environment uh so I
think if you look at uh new vehicle
sales uh across categories whether it is
Private Car whether it is uh two wheeler
or for the matter of fact commercial
vehicles uh I think we are seeing a lot
of uh positive momentum getting played
out a lot of it is also to do within the
context of the festive demand as well as
uh rural pickups so across the three
categories in so far as the market
momentum is concerned that's looking
very very positive uh that's why it's a
part of our earning call last last
evening we had also kind of put out what
has been the new vehicle volume sales
that one has seen in so far as the
market is concerned so hence in that
sense I think the demand momentum seems
to be looking very very positive uh now
let me put it in the context of how the
industry insurance industry has been
kind of also responding in so far as
motor as a segment is concerned
directionally if you see while the
combined ratio still stands elevated but
definitely it is kind of four to six
percentage better than what combined ISS
that the market has been operating let's
say one year back so again even from a
market perspective I think there seems
to be a sign of semblance that is kind
of possibly getting played out and and H
which is where the directional change
for improvement in Combined ratios is
also getting exhibited in so far as the
insurance Market is concerned and within
that now when I talk talk in the context
of I Lombard our approach to writing
risk whether it is for motor or whether
it is for any other category of
businesses we have always chosen to
drive profitable growth as a theme and
and and what we effectively try doing
doing as a part of this theme is
whenever we see uh opportunities of
growth we obviously kind of
significantly kind of uh deliver better
growth momentum but at the same time
when we as I said maybe for a couple of
years when the market has been at
elevated levels of competitive intensity
we have always been a bit guarded SL
cautious so it is in that context is
where maybe for the last couple of years
we have been growing a shade lower than
in so far as the market growth is
concerned particularly in the context of
motor
but what we are very happy in the
context of Isis Lombard is if you look
at the relative gap between what was
existing as industry growth numbers in
motor and is lomard growth num is in
motor that has been significantly coming
off with uh over the last I would say
pretty much on a sequential basis
quarter on quarter uh for the half year
for example the gap between industry
numbers and Lombard numbers were about
8% but for quarter 3 that Gap is down to
less than 4% and for the month of
December we actually have kind of
outgrown the market so hence I think we
are very very positive and optim
optimistic in the way how one is seeing
the growth momentum play out in motor as
a category and for is I think we rightly
positioned to capitalize that
opportunity for growth in the context of
loss ratios uh I think on motor I think
again we are quite comfortable at the
loss ratio ranges that you are seeing
for us on 9 months which for the segment
has been at an aggregate at about 65% I
think the range that we have generally
tooke to the market is comfortable in
the range of 65 to 67% so at this point
of time I think whatever we are seeing
on the loss ratio Trends from an is
standpoint I think we are quite
comfortable at the range at which we are
operating at right sir so also um on the
on the side on the bit of retail Health
here uh we have finally reported a
profit versus the loss that we've been
seeing for the past couple of quarters
so what has changed are we going to be
able to maintain the same momentum that
we are seeing on the retail Health front
and what are the steps that we are
taking to uh now uh sort of grow further
on the retail Health side also in the
group health the losses have narrowed
down so what is the company now doing to
take on more business or uh have we are
we seeing better because you know now
that Co is entirely behind us although
now we're again seeing a bit of cases
here and there first of all do you see
that as a threat to uh retail and
corporate uh Health policies and going
forward and also how has it been for the
quarter so there are two too many uh too
many uh questions in into one uh let me
try let me try and answer all of them
let me pick up the last Fe one which is
relatively an easier one to call out uh
I think in so far as the covid uh uh
come back is concerned at this stage
nothing to call out uh uh we are not
necessarily seeing any uh increases in
so far as uh hospitalization SL need for
insurance payments are concerned in the
context of what possibly one had
anticipated in terms of a covid wave but
at this point of time nothing to call
out nothing to kind of worry about in so
far as uh the covid cases are concerned
uh now let me kind of try to address the
points that you had in the context of
retail Health as well as corporate
Health uh retail health for us as we
have been talking through has been an
area of investment because that's a
segment which we are significantly in
the past we we were underinvested and
that's the reason our market share on
retail Health stands at about 3%
relative to the company market share
which is at almost close to about 8.6
8.7% levels there about uh so that's an
area where we believe there's an
opportunity for us to significantly
Drive growth and hence to that extent is
where we are kind of investing in
expanding distribution whether it is in
terms of adding our own head count of
employees to drive retail Health
distribution and therefore who in turn
will kind of go out to the market and
get incremental number of retail Health
agents on both the fronts I think we are
very very happy with the way how the
expansion initiatives have played out
and hence in that sense we will continue
to make investments in driving growth
and improve market share on retail
Health as a category and that's why even
if you look at for that particular
segment for the 9 months our growth was
roughly slightly more than 19% industy
growth numbers was a shared lower than
19% so in that sense we have been able
to get some marginal market share
but honestly there's a lot more that we
can do in the context of driving growth
in that particular segment uh in terms
of offerings I think we continuously
keep to look for how we can improve the
product proposition particularly in the
context of retail health and we have
been doing that even in the past and we
will continue to kind of look for
different product features that we can
introduce in the market whether it is
for different age groups whether it is
for different lifestyle related uh ways
of living etc etc on the health side
from an is SHP point you will continue
to uh hear us a lot more as we move
along in terms of new products that one
will introduce uh uh in the market uh in
terms of uh the loss ratios range on
retail Health inity again we have talked
about us comfortable operating in the
loss ratio range of anywhere between 65
to 70% and if you have looked at the 9
month numbers the retail Health inunity
loss ratios has been at around 66% or
there about so again there again we are
quite comfortable at the loss ratio
range that we are operating at but as I
said we will continue to uh expand on uh
driving uh distribution and service in
order to capture the opportunity on the
retail Health front quickly on the
corporate Health side uh again I think
the growth momentum is looking very very
positive uh in the market there seems to
be kind of uh an improvement in pricing
that we are seeing in the segment and
hence we are able to kind of capture
incremental opportunity and that's why
we are definitely growing much much
faster in so far as the market is
concerned on the group health side again
on the loss ratios front what we have
talked about is being comfortable in the
loss ratio range anywhere between 94 to
95% and if you would have looked at the
9 Monon reported numbers for us on
corporate health or group health the
loss ratio was at about 95% so on both
the segments I think both in terms of
the growth momentum and the loss
experience for we are quite comfortable
with so then is it safe to assume that
the combined I show guidance that you
given for fi25 at 102% will be in sight
or are we expecting some um delay or
Miss there so honestly if you ask us I
think uh at this point again let me just
put this in context uh what we have
talked about to the market is to get to
as you rightly indicated getting to a
combined rati of 102% by the end of
fi25 U and if you look at the market
combined ratios is still operating at
about 112 uh in so far as is Lombard is
concerned at this point of time we are
sticking to the combined ratio
trajectory of getting to 102 by the end
of next financial year and if you see
directionally the path that we have been
taking even if you look at the current
year numbers it seems to kind of clearly
indicate that we are on the right course
and therefore to that extent we are on
course to stick to that 102% numbers by
the end of next financial year uh if the
market improves the combined ratios from
the current levels uh in fact it could
be the other way around of possibly us
looking at possibly accelerating maybe
the expectation of reaching 102% by the
end of next financial year so obviously
we will kind of watch for how the market
response and maybe in a quarter or two
we will come back and possibly see if
there's a need for us to accelerate the
102% combin issues that we have spoken
about for meeting by the end of next
financial year so I'm going to have my
last two questions very quick uh one is
on the Marine Insurance front we have
issues at the Red Sea and there there
are talks that private insurers are are
indicating a pullback or are uh leading
to uh certain price increases for uh
insurances on that route um is that the
case and we we've had a phenomenal
quarter on Marine insurance as well so
what do you think would be uh the
guidance for quarter 4 because these
issues are now creeping in and the last
is budget expectations sir yeah so I
think so if you look at on the Marine
side I mean we are pretty much uh kind
of still offering coverages uh at a
price that we are kind of comfortable
with and therefore to that extent is
what we have been doing
for not just Marine as a category if you
look at across portfolios the levels of
pricing at which we are comfortable with
is where we have been kind of
underrating the risk set and that's the
reason when you look at commercial lines
as a category which includes Marine
insurance as well it has been generally
profitable for Isis Al Lombard because
of the nature of risk selection criteria
that we have been able to put in the
market so hence to that extent I think
that's also seems continues to and if
you look at the opportunity that that
segment presents as you rightly
indicated log Logistics is doing
fantastic phenomenally phenomenally very
well so therefore on Commercial lines
including Marine insurance we will
continue to outgrow the market however
we will obviously be again as as we keep
saying be mindful of what does it
translate to in terms of loss
experiences at this point of time no
concerns it still continues to be a
profitable portfolio for it as a
category uh on the budget expectations I
think uh uh I think there is obviously
when you look at in the context of uh
the retail customers there is always an
expectation that one should increase uh
limits in so far as tax deductions are
concerned depending on the various
insurance requirements uh that you have
uh so hence that could be one possible
ask that could come through in so far as
the budget needs are concerned and the
second I would say is if you look at
increasingly we are getting to see a lot
more catastrophic events play out for
example this year we have seen three
catastrophic events every year every
quarter we had seen one event play out
so therefore the need for home
insurances is significantly pretty much
there today a lot many individuals do
not necessarily kind of cover their
homes or even if someone covers their
home they do not cover their contents
etc etc the opportuni is humongous if
there is some form of an incentivization
that the budget could outlay in this
context I think that again that could be
a great positive uh in so far as the
budget ask is concerned thank you so
much for joining us today sir and thank
you
[Music]
viewers